{
    "questions" : [
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "60_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Woman : How can I help you?\nMan : This wallet, I think someone lost it. I was in front of this.\nWoman : Yes, this way, please.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "60_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : Sumiya, are you okay? It must hurt a lot.\nWoman : Yes, I can't get up because my legs hurt.\nMan : Is that so? I'll help you, so wake up slowly.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "60_3_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : How do office workers spend their lunch time? The lunch time for office workers was 70% for one hour, 20% for an hour and a half, and 10% for less than an hour. After meals, 'drinking tea with colleagues' was the most common activity, followed by 'walking' and 'sleeping in a nap'.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "4. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  장소를 다시 말해 주세요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  다음 모임은 안 갈 거예요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이번 주에 만나면 좋겠어요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  정문 옆에 있는 식당이에요.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Minsu, the meeting place has changed this week.\nMan : Is that so? Where did it go.\nWoman : It's the restaurant next to the front door.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  정문 옆에 있는 식당이에요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "5. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  아침 일찍 기차를 탔어.",
            "option_2"      : "②  표가 없어서 아직 못 갔어.",
            "option_3"      : "③  표가 있는지 한번 알아볼게.",
            "option_4"      : "④  금요일 오후 표는 취소하자.",
            "detail"        : "Man : I looked up the train ticket, but I don't think there are any tickets for Friday afternoon.\nWoman : Then how about Saturday morning?\nMan: I'll see if there are any tickets.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  표가 있는지 한번 알아볼게.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "6. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  발표는 늘 어렵지요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  계획부터 세워 보세요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  외국어 공부를 좀 할까 해요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  학기가 시작되면 많이 바빠요.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : After tomorrow's presentation, this semester is over.\nMan : I know. Sumi, have you made any plans for your vacation?\nWoman : I'm very busy when the semester starts.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  외국어 공부를 좀 할까 해요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "7. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  응. 시골에서 산 적이 있어.",
            "option_2"      : "②  아니. 너무 지루해서 졸았어.",
            "option_3"      : "③  아니. 드라마 볼 시간이 없었어.",
            "option_4"      : "④  응. 두 사람 보면서 한참 웃었어.",
            "detail"        : "Man : The new drama I started this time. It was really fun.\nWoman : Oh, the story of a child who lives with his grandmother in the countryside?\nMan : No. I didn't have time to watch the drama.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  응. 두 사람 보면서 한참 웃었어.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "8. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  만족도가 높은 편입니다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  조사 결과가 나왔습니다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  프로그램이 적은 것 같습니다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  질문을 다시 정리해 보겠습니다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Team leader, I made a program satisfaction survey. Can you please check.\nMan : Let's see. Well, I think there are a lot of questions.\nWoman : I have a high level of satisfaction.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  질문을 다시 정리해 보겠습니다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "9. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  그릇 색깔을 고른다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  그릇 가격을 물어본다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  전시할 그릇을 바꾼다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자에게 그릇을 준다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : The bowls on display are so unique and cool.\nWoman : Isn't it? They also sell it, so let's buy one.\nMan : Then how about that blue bowl?\nWoman : That's fine. I'll go find out how much it is",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  그릇 가격을 물어본다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "10. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  서류를 찾는다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  신분증을 꺼낸다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  카드를 보여 준다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  신청서를 작성한다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Customer, are you going to use this card?\nWoman : Yes. But does the card come out right away?\nMan : Sure. I'll help you fill out the documents. Can I have your ID please?\nWoman : Yes, wait a minute.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  신분증을 꺼낸다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "11. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  건전지를 가지러 간다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  현재 시간을 확인한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  시계를 벽에서 내린다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  건전지를 서랍에 넣는다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Sister, I don't think the wall clock is going. I think the battery is out.\nWoman : Oh, that's right. I think where was the battery....... \nMan : There will be a few in the main room drawer. I'll bring.\nWoman : No. I'll find it, so please put down your watch.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  건전지를 가지러 간다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "12. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  회의 자료를 만든다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  회의 자료를 출력한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  거래처 직원을 만난다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  거래처에 일정을 알린다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Mr. Lee Soo-mi, are you ready for the meeting and materials with your client? I'd like to see you before the meeting.\nWoman : Do you want me to print out the data now?\nMan : Yes, please pick it right away. You told the client the time and place, right?\nWoman: I sent you a confirmation email yesterday.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  회의 자료를 출력한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "13. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 봉사 활동을 시작하려고 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자는 봉사 활동 때문에 고민하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 봉사 활동 검색 사이트를 이용해 봤다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 여자와 함께 봉사 활동을 한 적이 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I want to do volunteer work, but it's my first time, so I don't know what to do.\nMan : There is an Internet site that introduces volunteer activities, do you want me to tell you?\nWoman : Yes, I like it. Have you ever used Minsu, too?\nMan : Sure. It's convenient because there are various types and you can choose the period.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  여자는 봉사 활동 때문에 고민하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "14. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  점검은 내일 할 예정이다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  오전에 점검이 모두 끝난다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  비상벨이 여러 번 울릴 것이다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  점검이 시작되면 밖으로 나가야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Residents, there is an inspection of the apartment firefighting facility today. Buildings 1 to 5 will be inspected from 9 a.m. to 12 a.m., and buildings 6 to 10 will be inspected from 1 to 4 p.m. The emergency bell will ring several times during today's inspection, so please don't be surprised and continue what you are doing.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  비상벨이 여러 번 울릴 것이다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "15. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  간판이 떨어져서 다친 사람이 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  태풍은 오늘 밤에 더 강해질 것이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이번 태풍의 특징은 비가 많이 오는 것이다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  제주도는 아직 태풍의 영향을 받고 있지 않다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Currently, the typhoon is passing through Jeju Island. It is raining in Jeju Island with strong winds. This typhoon is particularly damaged by the wind. In Jeju City, two citizens were seriously injured because of the signboard. The typhoon will pass through the East Sea late tonight.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  간판이 떨어져서 다친 사람이 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "16. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  한국에는 이 일을 하는 사람이 많다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  꼼꼼한 사람은 이 일에 맞지 않는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 일을 하는 데에 자격증은 필요 없다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 일을 할 때 예술적 감각이 도움이 된다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : You successfully finished this fireworks festival, right? There are only a few fireworks directors in Korea, so what do I need to become a fireworks director? Man: First of all, you have to have a license. It's meticulous and calm to deal with dangerous goods.I have a good personality These days, it explodes according to the music, so it's better to have an artistic sense.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  이 일을 할 때 예술적 감각이 도움이 된다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "17. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  오래 볼 수 있는 꽃이 좋다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  관리가 쉬운 식물을 사고 싶다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  식물은 집 밖에서 키워야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  집에 꽃이 많은 화분이 있어야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : How about this? The size of the flower pot is suitable and the shape of the tree is pretty. You don't have to water it often, so it's easy to raise it.\nWoman : Well, I prefer a flower pot with a lot of flowers than that.......\nMan : The flowers lose quickly and become messy. Why don't you do this.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  관리가 쉬운 식물을 사고 싶다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "18. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  신청서에 쓸 정보를 줄이면 좋겠다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  신청서 쓰는 방법을 안내해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  신청자 요구에 맞는 수업을 해야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  수업 내용을 미리 알려 주는 것이 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : There are too many things to write on the application form. Do I even need to use a job to apply for a class at the cultural center?\nWoman : It's because if you know the applicant well, you can give you a class that meets your needs.\nMan : You can ask that separately. I think I'm asking for too much information.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  신청서에 쓸 정보를 줄이면 좋겠다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "19. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  아이들 책은 무겁지 않아야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  아이들 책은 온라인으로 사야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  아이들 책은 전문가의 추천이 중요하다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  아이들 책은 직접 본 후에 사는 게 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Honey, I need to buy some children's books, can you order them online?\nMan : Why don't you see it in person?\nWoman : It was recommended by an expert. And the book is heavy, so it's hard to buy it and bring it.\nMan : But the kids will see it, so we have to look at the contents first and buy it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  아이들 책은 직접 본 후에 사는 게 좋다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "20. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  시사 프로그램은 일반인에게 인기를 얻기 어렵다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  일반인의 눈높이에서 시사 문제를 전달해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  청취자가 참여하는 시사 프로그램을 만들고 싶다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  시사 프로그램 진행자는 청취자의 질문에 답해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Why is the current affairs program hosted by the reporter so popular?\nMan : I think of who the listener is first. The people who listen to our broadcast are ordinary people. So I constantly ask questions to professionals at the level of the general public. When a difficult expression comes out, I ask you to explain it again.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  일반인의 눈높이에서 시사 문제를 전달해야 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "21. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  교실의 불편한 점을 고쳐야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  빈 교실을 토론방으로 활용하는 게 좋다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  학생들의 팀별 과제를 늘릴 필요가 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  토론 수업을 위해 교실을 넓게 지어야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Principal, I had a meeting with the teachers last week. There was an opinion that the empty classroom in the basement should be used as a warehouse or discussion room.\nMan : Well, wouldn't a discussion room be better than a warehouse? There was a lot of talk about the lack of space for students to talk comfortably while preparing for team assignments.\nWoman : By the way, the classroom is dark and poorly ventilated, is it okay as a discussion room? The air conditioner is also not installed. Wouldn't that be possible to solve it?\nMan : It's a waste to use it as a warehouse.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  빈 교실을 토론방으로 활용하는 게 좋다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "22. 들은 내용으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  지하에 창고를 새로 만들었다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 빈 교실의 환기 문제를 해결했다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 지난주에 선생님들과 회의를 했다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  지하에 있는 교실에 에어컨을 모두 설치했다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Principal, I had a meeting with the teachers last week. There was an opinion that the empty classroom in the basement should be used as a warehouse or discussion room.\nMan : Well, wouldn't a discussion room be better than a warehouse? There was a lot of talk about the lack of space for students to talk comfortably while preparing for team assignments.\nWoman : By the way, the classroom is dark and poorly ventilated, is it okay as a discussion room? The air conditioner is also not installed. Wouldn't that be possible to solve it?\nMan : It's a waste to use it as a warehouse.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  여자는 지난주에 선생님들과 회의를 했다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  정장 대여 방법을 알아보고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  정장 대여 날짜를 문의하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  정장 대여 가격을 확인하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  정장 대여 예약을 변경하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : That's the youth hope center, right? I called you because I heard that you can borrow the suit you wear for the interview for free. What should I do?\nWoman : This service is available to any citizen of Inju who lives in Inju. You can apply a week before the company interview. You can apply for a rental on the website. You can choose the clothes you want on the website and bring your ID on the day you made the reservation.\nMan : Can I get a suit by courier?\nWoman : Yes, you can send a copy of your ID by email and pay the delivery fee.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  정장 대여 방법을 알아보고 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "24. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  센터에서 신청자가 입을 옷을 골라 준다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  센터에 가서 정장 대여 신청서를 내야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 서비스로 신청한 옷을 택배로 받기는 어렵다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 서비스는 인주시에 살고 있어야 이용할 수 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : That's the youth hope center, right? I called you because I heard that you can borrow the suit you wear for the interview for free. What should I do?\nWoman : This service is available to any citizen of Inju who lives in Inju. You can apply a week before the company interview. You can apply for a rental on the website. You can choose the clothes you want on the website and bring your ID on the day you made the reservation.\nMan : Can I get a suit by courier?\nWoman : Yes, you can send a copy of your ID by email and pay the delivery fee.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  이 서비스는 인주시에 살고 있어야 이용할 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "25. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  아이들이 노는 놀이터는 공간이 넓을수록 좋다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  놀이터에 다양한 놀이 기구를 더 설치해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  놀이 기구가 없는 놀이터는 상상력을 기르기에 좋다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  놀이터에 있는 놀이 기구의 관리를 철저히 해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : How is the playground you made different from the existing playground?\nMan : This place is bigger and wider than the existing playground, but there are no rides like swings or slides. Instead, there are sand fields and a stream of water, and there are also small hills. There are also old logs next to the hill. When they come here, children climb hills, ride logs, and play in the water in the stream. Because there are no rides, children have unlimited imagination. Here, children are free to play while doing new things in different ways.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  놀이 기구가 없는 놀이터는 상상력을 기르기에 좋다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "26. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 놀이터는 기존 놀이터보다 작아졌다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  안전을 위해 놀이터의 통나무들을 치웠다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 놀이터에서 아이들이 물놀이를 할 수 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  놀이터 안에 모래밭을 없애고 언덕을 만들었다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : How is the playground you made different from the existing playground?\nMan : This place is bigger and wider than the existing playground, but there are no rides like swings or slides. Instead, there are sand fields and a stream of water, and there are also small hills. There are also old logs next to the hill. When they come here, children climb hills, ride logs, and play in the water in the stream. Because there are no rides, children have unlimited imagination. Here, children are free to play while doing new things in different ways.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  이 놀이터에서 아이들이 물놀이를 할 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        }
    ]
}
